{
    "id": "afb74c21ce324c44a9e666a3d04e4b11",
    "title": "Relative Pronouns Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Everyone respects people ……………… are honest.",
            "description": "We use who to refer to people and which to refer to things or animals. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "6ba247a738ee4a389316134c1d92393b"
        },
        {
            "question": "We saw the dog ………………… chased the cat.",
            "description": "Both 'that' and 'which' can refer to animals or things. ",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "which",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "6b624ddbf2794a81b2f52432ab268be0"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ……………….. does his best shall be rewarded.",
            "description": "The relative pronoun 'who' acts as the subject of the relative clause.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whose",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "0ab3176847fd473fa84994f09be887c1"
        },
        {
            "question": "I know ………………… you mean.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "what",
                "that",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c224540d8a4e4265b29ac45383244c93"
        },
        {
            "question": "She has gone to Mangalore ………………… is her native place.",
            "description": "'That' is not possible in non-identifying relative clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "which",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "5249cfd349604fdba24019c5b3d94091"
        },
        {
            "question": "I have never seen the bird ………………… you are talking about.",
            "description": "In identifying relative clauses, both 'that' and 'which' are possible. ",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "which",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "19df4a5c4f634ab088fb19d07f9b8428"
        },
        {
            "question": "I know the man ………………… kidnapped the child.",
            "description": "Use 'who' to refer to people. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "5e185f12a7ef4264a8cd31cfa2643510"
        },
        {
            "question": "You must give away ………………. you do not need.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "what",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "bfa3e824ca6d44cfad82e6d62a5b12e4"
        },
        {
            "question": "There is no one ………………….. has not lost a dear one.",
            "description": "In identifying relative clauses 'who' and 'that' are both possible. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "436d7871c83c4c64843d92a5dda57472"
        },
        {
            "question": "Here is the phone ………………. you lost.",
            "description": "In identifying relative clauses both 'that' and 'which' can be used to refer to things. ",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "which",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "ff7d8685eccb4d9e9de5cc8ee7435212"
        }
    ]
}